만약, 고양이 그르릉한다고 말하거나
그 고양이가 쥐를 잡는다고 한다면,
>> If I say the cat purrs or
this cat hunts mice, it's
그것은 새끼고양이 그르릉한다고 말하거나
새끼고양이가 쥐를 잡는다와 완벽히 동일합니다.
perfectly reasonable to also say the
kitty purrs or this kitty hunts mice.
이 상황은 그 단어들이 유사하다는 생각을
할 수 있도록 합니다.
The context gives you a strong
idea that those words are similar.
그르릉하고 쥐를 잡기 위해서는
고양이와 비슷해야 합니다.
You have to be catlike to purr and
hunt mice.
그래서, 단어의 상황을 예측하기 위해서는
배워보도록 합니다.
So, let's learn to
predict a word's context.
단어의 상황을 잘 예측하는 모델은
The hope is that a model that's good at
predicting a word's context will have to
고양이와 고양이 새끼를 유사하게 다루고,
그것들을 함께 가져가는 경항이 있습니다.
treat cat and kitty similarly, and
will tend to bring them closer together.
이 방법의 장점은 그 단어가 실제로
무슨 의미를 갖는지에 대해서 고려할 필요가 업습니다.
The beauty of this approach is that you
don't have to worry about what the words
그 단어들에 속한 무리들에
직접적으로 주어준 의미.. ???
actually mean, giving further meaning
directly by the company they keep.
유사한 단어가 유사한 상황에서 발생한다는
아이디어를 사용하는 많은 방법이있다.
There are many way to use this idea that
similar words occur in similar contexts.
우리의 경우에는, 작은 vector로 단어를
맵핑하는데 사용할 것입니다.
In our case, we're going to use
it to map words to small vectors
서로에게 근접하도록 하는 embeddings
이라고 불러지는
called embeddings which are going
to be close to each other
단어가 유사한 의미를 갖을때는,
그리고 유사하지 않을때는 멀리 떨어뜨림.
when words have similar meanings,
and far apart when they don't.
Embedding은 희소성 문제를 해결합니다.
Embedding solves of
the sparsity problem.
한편 단어를 작은 vector로 embedded하고
Once you have embedded your word into
this small vector, now you have a word
고양이와 비슷한 단어들 cat, kitties
pets, lione을 표현할 수 있습니다.
representation where all the catlike
things like cats, kitties, kittens,
매우 유사한 vector로..
pets, lions, are all represented
by vectors that are very similar.
이 모델은 새로운 것을 학습할
필요가 없습니다.
Your model no longer has
to learn new things for
고양이에 대한 언급할 수 있는 모든 방법을..
every way there is to talk about a cat.
이것은 고양이와 같은 것들을 특정 패턴을
일반화할 수 있습니다.
It can generalize from this
particular pattern of catlike things.